<resources>
    <string name="app_name">NiftyDriverApp</string>
    <string name="title_Profile">Profile</string>
    <string name="title_StartTrip">Start Trip</string>
    <string name="title_TripView">Trip View</string>
    <string name="title_MyTrips">My Trips</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>


    <string name="terms"><b>AGREEMENT TO TERMS</b>\n\nThese Terms and Conditions constitute a legally binding agreement made between you and the developer.\n\nPlease make sure you drive carefully, follow all traffic laws and speed limits in your nation, and stop in a secure location before you take your measurements. Do not race or use the system for excessive speed. While driving, avoid looking at the display. Nifty Driver App is not liable for any harm done to people or property of any type. The Nifty Driver App Company disclaims responsibility for any smartphone issues or data loss brought on by using the app. You do it at your own risk when using this application. Actual values and measurements may differ. Values can change and fluctuate depending on a variety of factors.\n\n<b>Data privacy information:</b>\n\nThis app only stores data locally and makes it available through the app or direct access to the phone file store. It does not share driving or performance data with any servers. For the purpose of replaying a driving session to the driver, geographic positions are used to record the session. No dependencies receive the geographic position data.This indicates that all data and login information are wiped along with the application if you remove it.\nFor further information, please send an email to paisa8822@hotmail.com.\n\nThe smart phone should be placed level and well-aligned in the same direction as the car, as seen in the image below. Place your vehicle in a level, flat parking space and change the device orientation. It ought to be flat and facing the same way as the car.\n\nThe Nifty Driver App is developed by a student from Charles Sturt University in Australia. </string>
</resources>


